SIMRAN AMIN

PROFILE

I graduated from the University of Cambridge in 2017 where I studied Natural Sciences, specialising in pathology and pharmacology. I went on to study Dentistry at the University of Liverpool where I graduated with Honours and achieved two Distinctions in Oral Diseases and Oral Health. Alongside my clinical training I enjoy working digitally with four years working remotely as an editor where I provided digital examination resources for prospective medical school applicants and created guidance documentation for onboarding new writers. With my interest in technology, writing and design, I intend to pivot towards an alternative career in health or tech where I can develop an expertise, support a wider cause and balance autonomous work with collaborative input.

EDUCATION

2017-2021 University of Liverpool (4 years)

Bachelor of Dental Surgery with Honours (Graduate Entry Pathway)

Distinction in Oral Diseases Distinction in Oral Health

2014-2017 University of Cambridge (3 years)

Natural Sciences - Bachelor of Arts with Honours

Part II: High 2:1 (69%) - Pharmacology

Part 1B: High 2:1 (69%) - Pathology, Pharmacology, Developmental Biology Part 1A: High 2:1 (67%) - Physiology, Cellular Biology, Chemistry, Maths

2007-2014 The Tiffin Girls' School, Kingston upon Thames

A-levels: A2 Biology (A*) A2 Chemistry (A*) A2 Maths (A*), AS Art (A)

GCSEs: 11, 10 at grade A* including Maths, English Language, French, Spanish OCR Level 2 Certificate in Creative iMedia (Website design, Video editing)

DIGITAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Adobe Photoshop | Procreate | Microsoft Powerpoint, Excel and Word | Basic HTML/CSS | Figma

Portfolio Project (ongoing): http://simranamin.com/

2023-present Documenting APIs: A guide for technical writers and engineers

Introduced to the process of writing API documentation, understanding its necessity for developers and learning to use tools such as Postman and StopLight to create

documentation conforming to the OpenAl specification.

2023 Coursera: Stanford University - Writing in the Sciences Course (with Honors)

Learnt the principles of clear scientific writing, practised editing samples of

scientific text and peer reviewed assignments from other participants.

2023 freeCodeCamp: Responsive Web Design Certification

> Learnt basic HTML/CSS to create a variety of webpages including a survey form. tribute page, product landing page, technical documentation page and personal

portfolio

2016 Institute of Digital Marketing: Creative Data Academy (3 day workshop)

Selected to learn about principles of data analysis and participated in marketing

projects for companies such as Mercedes Benz and Feel Unique

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

2021	MFDS Part 1 (Royal College of Surgeons of England)
2020	ABAOMS Essay Prize
	Liverpool winner for essay titled 'The Impact of Human Factors on Oral Surgery'
2019	Dental Alumni Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Oral Science & Medicine Knowledge Examinations
2019	Mark Ball Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Evidence Based Virtual Case Report Presentation
2018	Robert Grieve Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 2 nd BDS Oral Science and Medicine Critical Reasoning Paper
2017	Churchill College Academic Prize
	For attaining high examination results in Part II pharmacology

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2022-present Family Dental Practice: PLVE Dentist (1 year)

 Providing both NHS and private treatments while working to complete my postgraduation training, in continuation from the previous role

2021-2022 Together Dental Wandsworth: Dental Foundation Trainee (4 months)

- Provided preventative and basic general dental care within a diverse high needs NHS practice
- Carried out local audits on hand hygiene, infection control, radiographic record keeping and staff documentation

2017-2021 Medify: UCAT Abstract Reasoning Editor (4 years)

- Remotely trained new members of the team and created written guides to support new question writers with question writing and admin interfaces
- Reviewed and edited submissions from question writers to regulate quality and ensure clarity of written explanations
- Created practice questions and mock examinations conforming to the UCAT specification
- Responsible for managing and resolving web content problems reported by Medify users over peak exam season

OTHER POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

2015-2017 University of Cambridge: President of Churchill College Art Society

- Organised and lead weekly drawing, painting and origami sessions
- Managed the annual budget for art expenses
- Commissioned by Churchill College to illustrate a Fresher's week backdrop

ARTICLES AND PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Amin, S. (2018). 'Are you considering Graduate Dentistry?', UniAdmissions
- Amadeu de Oliveira, F., MacVinish, L. J., Amin, S., Herath, D., Jeggle, P., Mela, I., Pieri, M., Sharma, C., Jarvis, G. E., Levy, F. M., Santesso, M. R., Khan, Z. N., Leite, A. L., Oliveira, R. C., Buzalaf, M. A. R. and Edwardson, J. M. (2018) 'The effect of fluoride on the structure, function, and proteome of intestinal epithelia', *Environmental Toxicology*, 33(1), pp. 63-71. doi: 10.1002/TOX.22495.